(サスケ)今度は俺の作戦でいく。
協力しろ。
This time, we're going
with my strategy.
Help me out.
(ゼツ)母さん
こいつら やっかいだね。
Mother…
These two are quite annoying.
もうさ こいつら分けちまえば？
Why don't you split them up…
そして １匹ずつ…。
and take them on separately?
うっ！
(ナルト)サスケ！
Sasuke!
(ゼツ)これで
もう母さんを封印できない。
Now you won't be able
to seal Mother away…
まずは お前のチャクラを
すべて吸い尽くす。
First, I'll suck out all of your chakra!
クソッ！
Damn it!
CONNECTING THOUGHTS
It's hard to believe.
(オビト)信じられんが→
So both your powers and Sasuke's
とにかく
そのカグヤってのを封印するには→
are necessary in order
to seal away this Kaguya?
ナルトとサスケの
２人の力が必要ってことだな。
Yeah! But like I said earlier,
I can't sense Sasuke at all!
あぁ でも さっきも言ったけど
サスケが感知できねえんだ。
(カカシ)氷が 動いてるな。
The ice…is moving.
あそこだ！
Over there!
くっ…。
《自然と一体化してやがる！》
She's merged with Nature!
かはっ！
Naruto!
(サクラ)ナルト！
やっと出てきやがったな。
She's finally showing herself.
サスケは急に感知できなくなった
と言ったな。
You said you suddenly stopped
sensing Sasuke?
あぁ。
Yeah.
Then I suspect he was taken
to another dimension.
なら 別空間へ飛ばされたと
想像できる。
もう一度 やつが空間をつなげ→
If I resonate my Kamui
the next time she connects
開いたと同時
俺の神威と共鳴させれば→
and opens a portal
to another Time-Space,
まず間違いなく入り込める。
I'm positive I can enter it.
そこに サスケがいれば→
If Sasuke is there, I can bring
him back to this dimension.
こっちに
連れて帰ってくることはできる。
ただ…
それには膨大なチャクラがいる。
However…
I'll need an enormous amount
of chakra to do it,
俺の時空間じゃないからな。
since it's not my own Time-Space.
向こうでチャクラが切れたら終わりだ。
If my chakra runs out
while I'm there, I'm done.
なら 俺も行く。
Then I'll go with you.
本体も
すぐにやられたりはしねえ。
The real me won't go down
that quickly.
Because I'm strong.
俺は 強えから。
Your Clone Chakra isn't enough.
分身の お前のチャクラでも足りない。
(サクラ)私の百豪のチャクラがあっても→
Would it still be inadequate
with my 100 Healings Chakra?
足りませんか？
それで 限度いっぱいだ。
That would give me
the bare minimum.
Both of you, come with me.
２人とも俺と来い。
はい。
All right!
(オビト)時間のない俺が→
I'm not going to waste time
on a speech,
今更 詭弁をたれるつもりはない。
because I'm almost out of time.
But…
ただ
せめて お前たちの前を歩いて…。
I just ask that you let me
walk in front of you…
死なせてくれ。
and die for you.
《やっぱりそうだ。
Then it's true.
This man can't be saved.
この人 もう助からないんだ。
だから 死ぬ気で…》
That's why he intends to die…
サスケが その空間にいるかどうかも
わからない。
We don't even know if Sasuke
is in that Time-Space.
だが まずは やつの懐に入り→
But we'll start by getting
into close range with her.
サスケは必ず俺が見つけ
お前の本体まで届ける。
I promise to find Sasuke,
and deliver him to the real you.
オビト 俺のことを助けてくれて
ありがとう。
Obito.
Thanks for rescuing me…
そして サスケまで…。
And Sasuke too.
こんな俺に礼など言うな。
Don't thank someone like me.
敵を見てろ。
Just keep an eye on the enemy.
もう 面はねえんだな。
So no more masks, huh?
俺は カカシの友であり→
I'm Kakashi's friend,
お前の父の部下であり→
your father's subordinate,
サスケと同じ うちはであり
そして…。
I'm an Uchiha just
like Sasuke,
and…
((火影ってのは
痛えのを我慢して→
The Hokage is someone
who endures pain
みんなの前を
歩いてるやつのことだ。
and takes the lead in
front of everyone.
そして あいつの そういう
歩き方が仲間を引き寄せる。
The way he forges ahead
draws others towards him.
(つまずきそうなら助けたくなる))
He makes you want to reach out
when he's about to stumble.
I was your senior who dreamt
the same dream as you.
俺は… お前と同じ夢を見た
先輩だった。
ナルト そして サクラと言ったな。
Naruto!
And you said
your name was Sakura?
俺の体に触れておけ。
Keep a hand on me,
いつでも別空間へ飛べるように。
so we can teleport to a different
Time-Space at any moment.
(サクラ)はい。
Got it.
俺たちのこと バレてるな やっぱ。
She knows about us, after all.
神威でやつの空間へ
飛んだとしても→
We have to keep in mind
that even if we jump into
her dimension with Kamui,
感知されることを
考慮しておかないとな。
she'll perceive us.
《こちらは
気にもとめないってことか》
So we're not worth her attention, eh?
《そう こっちへ来い。
Yeah, come over here.
お前の狙いは 俺のチャクラだろ。
What you want…
is my chakra, right?!
バカでけえ術しても
吸収されちゃ意味ねえ。
Whatever jutsu I use,
she's just going to absorb it.
やっぱ こいつにも
いちばん効くのは陽動と体術だ。
So what will work best
on her is also…
a feint and taijutsu!
I can't use a pervy move
to distract her anymore.
出オチのおいろけ系は
もう陽動には使えねえ。
俺の基本に立ち返ってやるんだ。
So I gotta go back to the basics
それで追い込む。
and corner her!
If she tries to escape through
that weird window again,
こいつがまた あの変な扉から
逃げようとしたときに→
一緒に入る。
I'll enter it with her.
そこで サスケを捜す。
That's where I'll look for Sasuke!
今でもサスケのチャクラは
はっきり感じてんだ！》
Even now, I can sense
Sasuke's chakra clearly!
(カグヤ)ここは わらわの空間だ。
This is my Time-Space.
お前は何もできぬ。
You are powerless here.
(穆王)準備はできたな ナルト。
おう！
Are you ready, Naruto?
Yeah!
一気にチャクラを
沸点までもっていくぞ。
I'm going to boost your chakra
to the boiling point!
怪力無双！
Vapor Style: Unrivalled Strength!
うぉ～！
よっしゃ！
す すごい。
All right!
A-Amazing…
(九喇嘛)チャクラは
練っておいてやったぞ ナルト。
I infused chakra for you, Naruto!
サンキュー 九喇嘛。
Thank you, Kurama!
多重 影分身の術。
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
今 ここは
俺の空間だってばよ！
Right now,
this place is my Time-Space!
U...
うっ！
ずっ！
zu...
ma...
まっ！
きっ！
ki!
ナルト一帯連弾！
Naruto
Uzumaki
Barrage!
《開いたな。
It opened!
本体の俺が行く》
The real me will go!
ん!? 入り込めたのか？
He forced his way in?
バカな！
Impossible!
《ん!? 消えた？》
He disappeared?
(ゼツ)何匹か
入り込んでしまったようだな…。
Looks like several managed
to get in.
他の２匹は力尽きて 消えたか。
The other two ran out of power
and faded.
分身では
チャクラが もたなかったようだな。
Seems your clones didn't
have enough chakra.
お前が オリジナルか？
Are you the original Naruto?
なら どうだってんだ!?
So what if I am?
《ゼツ : 母さん…。
Mother, he's made it all the way
into this Root Time-Space.
こいつ この始球空間まで
入り込んできてる。
他の５つの空間へ
直接 つながる ここに→
It's not good that
he's here in this place
that connects directly
to the other five Time-Spaces.
こいつがいるのは まずいよ。
陰陽の力の共鳴で
サスケのところへ行かれかねない。
He might be able to get
to where Sasuke is,
using the resonance of
the dual opposite powers.
さっきの変な術にしろ→
Take that weird jutsu earlier,
このナルトという忍 昔から
何をするか わからない。
this shinobi Naruto has
always been unpredictable.
こいつは ここで
きっちり 殺しておくべきだ》
We ought to just…
kill him right now!
それは ダメよ。
We can't do that.
I must absorb
those children's chakra.
あの子たちのチャクラは
吸収しなくては。
《母さんが
世界の空間を変換するとき→
You use a huge amount of chakra
whenever you change
the Time-Space of the world, Mother.
多くのチャクラを使う。
今のチャクラは もしものときに
備えておく必要もある。
You need to preserve the chakra
you've got for an emergency.
これ以上 こいつとのやりとりを
のばさないほうがいい。
It's better if you don't keep
engaging him.
If you get sealed away,
all will be for naught.
もし 封印されれば 元も子もない。
確かに 多くのチャクラを
失うことになるが→
No doubt,
you'll lose a lot of chakra.
But you don't need his!
こいつの分は もう いらない。
It's better than having our long-
cherished plans turn to dust.
この長年の計画が
水の泡になるよりは ましだ》
(カグヤ)そうね。
You're right.
We can kill him with this!
《ゼツ : これで 殺せる。
共殺しの灰骨》
Murderous Bone Ash!
(ゼツ)死ね！
Die!
(ゼツ)これで 氷世界の分身も
すべて 消えたはずだ。
Now all of his clones
in the Ice World
should be gone as well!
(オビト)ナルトのおかげで うまく
俺の時空間へ隠れられたが→
Thanks to Naruto,
we were able to successfully hide
inside my Time-Space.
分身でも もう ナルトはいない。
But he's gone, even as a clone.
お前だけが頼りだ サクラ。
You're the only one
I can rely on, Sakura.
(サクラ)わかってます。
I know!
私だって 先頭を
走ってるつもりでいるんです。
There's a reason
I put myself at the front!
こうなったら
ナルト以上に結果を出しますよ。
And I'll do even more than Naruto!
((私なんかを好きになってくれた
バカだから。
He's the fool who fell
in love with me…
ナルトを いちばん苦しめてたのは
私だった。
I'm the one who made
Naruto suffer the most.
私は いつも 間違ってばかり。
失敗ばかり。
I was always wrong,
I always made mistakes.
I don't want to be wrong
ever again.
もう間違いたくない。
もう失敗したくない。
I don't want to make
a mistake ever again.
(だから もう引かない！))
That's why…
I'll never retreat!
((俺に任せてくれ サクラちゃん。
Leave it to me, Sakura!
いずれ 火影の名を名乗る
超エリート忍者 うずまきナルトという！
I'm the super elite ninja,
and future Hokage, Naruto Uzumaki!
覚えとけ！
Remember my name!
俺ってば 火影になって→
I'm going to become Hokage
(どの先代も
超えてやるんだってばよ！))
and surpass everyone
who came before me!
((かつてのあんたの バカげた夢は
今は もう…。
Your previously ridiculous dreams
no longer seem silly.
いかせない… いかせてたまるか！
I won't let you die!
I simply won't let you!
(絶対に
死なせるわけにはいかないのよ))
You're not going to die,
no matter what!
こっちが
うまく入れたようだね オビト。
Looks like we succeeded
in getting in, Obito.
《飛んだ先で いきなり
やられるなんてことは→
Now that you've teleported
over there,
please don't get crushed
on the other side!
勘弁してくれよ》
(ゼツ)オリジナルは殺した
なぜ消えていない？
We killed the original!
So why aren't they gone?
《本体の俺がいく》
The real me will go!
Damn it!
クソッ！
大丈夫だ ナルト。
Are you okay, Naruto?
これの どこが
大丈夫なんだってばよ。
How is this okay?!
Never mind. Just be ready
when Kaguya comes back.
いいから お前は カグヤが
戻ってきたときに備えていろ！
The Kamui worked.
神威はうまくいった。
気づかれた。
They're onto us!
I'll draw their attention,
俺がやつの注意を
引きつけるから→
so you two go hide
in the meantime!
その間に
２人は すぐ隠れてくれ。
I've marked this spot,
この場所はマーキングできた。
so I can hide in my Time-Space
for the time being.
いったん 俺の時空間へ身を隠す。
You too, Sakura!
サクラ お前もだ。
えっ？ あっ…。
The other two ran out
of power and faded.
他の２匹は力尽きて消えたか。
Seems your clones didn't
have enough chakra.
分身では チャクラが
もたなかったようだな。
お前がオリジナルか。
Are you the original Naruto?
なら どうだってんだ？
So what if I am?!
So they were just
clones back there.
向こうは すべて
ただの分身だったか 騙された。
You fooled us.
ヘヘ バレちまったか。
You got me.
I'm…
本当は俺がオリジナルだ。
the original.
I've gotta fight smart
and keep them busy
《こいつが向こうに
行かねえように→
so they don't go back over there.
うまく 戦わねえと》
This Time-Space should be
connected to the others.
この空間から
他の空間につながるはずだ。
We'll open them one by one
and look for Sasuke.
一つひとつ開いて サスケを捜し出す。
Right!
はい。
ハーッ！
I'll give him all the chakra I've got!
《ありったけのチャクラを この人に》
What an incredibly vast Time-Space…
とんでもなく遠い空間だ。
To be able to connect them
in an instant.
《これを一瞬でつなげるカグヤとは→
Just who is this Kaguya?!
いったい 何者だ？》
(サクラ)これって前にいた場所。
Isn't that where we were before?
ここは サスケを感知できない。
I can't sense Sasuke in there!
ハァ ハァ…。
大丈夫ですか？
Are you all right?
次だ。
On to the next!
はい。
Yes!
この辺りだと思ったがな。
I thought it was around here…
What is…that?
ここ 何？
ここでもない。
He's not here either.
うっ…。
少し休んだほうが。
You should rest a bit.
What about chakra?
チャクラは？
Oh… I still have reserves.
蓄えは まだあります。
戻る分は残しておけよ。
Keep enough to get back.
最悪 サスケが
見つからなかった場合は。
If worse comes to worst
and we can't find Sasuke…
We'll find him!
見つけます！
次だ。
Next!
うわ～。
Be careful about making
a gateway, Mother.
うかつに入り口を
作らないほうがいいよ 母さん。
ナルトが サスケに近づく。
Naruto will get closer to Sasuke.
Plus, I've figured out something.
それに１つわかったんだけど
ナルトのオリジナルには→
The original Naruto has
Truthseeker Orbs around him!
求道玉がついてる。
あ！
酸の海か。
A sea of acid!
大丈夫か!?
大丈夫です このくらい…。
Are you okay?
I'm fine!
お前は医療忍者だろ？
傷を治すまで待つ。
さっきのところも違ったな。
少し休んでから…。
そんなのいいです。
チャクラは限られているでしょ。
なぜ傷を治さない？
少しでも…。
ナルトがくれたチャンスを
潰すわけにはいかないもの！
つまずきそうなら
助けたくなる …か。
え？
いや。
さあ次だ。
はい！
ここか！
サスケ君！
サスケ君 こっち！
早く…。
《くっ まずい…》
《サスケ君》
うお～！
しゃ～んなろ～！
うう！
サスケ君！
うう！ ハア ハア…。
《そんな…》
どうやって？
これが 俺の能力だ。
俺と 離れた空間を
一瞬で入れ替える。
その距離は一定で
決まっているが。
おかげで届いた。